Long live the fighters.
Dune: Part Two is a science fiction, adventure
film directed by Denis Villeneuve.
Follow the mythic journey of Paul Atreides as he unites with Chani and the Fremen while
on a path of revenge against the conspirators who destroyed his family.
Facing a choice between the love of his life and the fate of the known universe,
Paul endeavors to prevent a terrible future only he can foresee.
Paul Atreides, played by Timothée Chalamet.
Chani, played by Zendaya.
Jessica, played by Rebecca Ferguson.
Stilgar, played by Javier Bardem.
Gurney Halleck, played by Josh Brolin.
Feyd-Rautha, played by Austin Butler.
Dune: Part Two is a 2024 American epic space opera film directed by Denis
Villeneuve, who co-wrote the screenplay with Jon Spaihts.
The sequel to Dune (2021), it is the second of a two-part adaptation of the 1965 novel Dune by
Frank Herbert, and the second installment of Villeneuve's Dune film trilogy.
It follows Paul Atreides as he unites with the Fremen people of the
desert planet Arrakis to wage war against House Harkonnen.
Timothée Chalamet, Zendaya, Rebecca Ferguson, Josh Brolin, Stellan Skarsgård, Dave Bautista, Charlotte Rampling, and Javier Bardem reprise
their roles from the first film, with Austin Butler, Florence Pugh, Christopher Walken, and Léa Seydoux joining the cast.
Development began after Legendary Entertainment acquired film and
television rights for the Dune franchise in 2016.
Villeneuve signed on as director in 2017, intending to make a
two-part adaptation of the novel due to its complexity.
Production contracts were only secured for the first film before the second film was
greenlit by Legendary in October 2021, subject to the success of the first.
Principal photography took place in Budapest, Italy, Jordan,
and Abu Dhabi between July and December 2022.
Delayed from a November 2023 release date due to the 2023 Hollywood labor disputes, Dune: Part
Two premiered at the Auditorio Nacional in Mexico City on February 6, 2024.
It was released in the United States on March 1, to positive reviews  and grossed $715 million
worldwide, surpassing its predecessor and becoming the seventh highest-grossing film of 2024.
It received numerous accolades, including being named one of the
top 10 films of 2024 by the American Film Institute.
It received five nominations at the 97th Academy Awards (including Best
Picture), winning Best Sound and Best Visual Effects.
It also won two BAFTAs for Best Sound and Best Special Visual Effects, and received two
nominations at the 82nd Golden Globe Awards, including Best Motion Picture – Drama.
Dune: Part Three, a third film based on Herbert's 1969 novel Dune Messiah, is in
production and scheduled to be released on December 18, 2026.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
sandstorm, chosen one, romance, tragedy.
The tone is thought_provoking.